Azeem Akram Solangi

Senior PHP Developer

Email: azeem.akram78@gmail.com

Mobile: **+923332828275** Skype: **azeemakram555**

Summary

Enthusiastic and professional Web Developer with 6 years of working experience in Software Industry. Strong background using OOP methodologies; strong knowledge of MVC.

I enjoy being part of a successful and productive team, to work on challenging tasks.

Quick to grasp new ideas and concepts, and to develop innovative and creative solutions to problems.

Able to work well on my own and can demonstrate the high levels of motivation required to meet the deadlines. Even under significant pressure, I possess a strong ability to perform effectively, able to take on multiple projects simultaneously

Skills & Expertise

Languages: PHP

Front End Technologies: Java Script, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS

CMS: Word Press, Joomla, Magneto, Self-created CMS

Framework: CodeIgniter, Symfony2, Laravel

Database: MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle, MS Access

Web Services: REST

Payment Gateways: PayPal

Integration with Social Sites: Facebook, Twitter, Google Plus

Code Repository: SVN, GITHUB, Git

Bug Reporting: Jira

IDEs: Dream Weaver, Net Beans, Eclipse, Notepad

ORM: Doctrine

Experience

Senior PHP Developer at Golive(June 2015 – Present)

Senior PHP Developer/Team Lead working on Symfony2, Doctrine Entity, Laravel, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, JQUERY, and PHP

Responsible for interacting with clients, requirements gathering, designing and implementation of the requirements specified by client.

Web Developer at Centric Source(March 2013 - May 2015)

Web Developer worked on Symfony2, Doctrine Entity, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, JQUERY, and PHP at LoveThatFit Team at Centric Source.

I am responsible for interacting with clients, understanding the requirements, designing and implementation of the requirements specified by client.

Web Developer at Outsourcemantra(March 2012 - February 2013)

WEB Developer worked on

PHP, MYSQL, CODEIGNITER (MVC), WORDPRESS, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, JOUERY.

Web Developer at Arpur Technologies (February 2011 - February 2012)

WEB Developer worked on PHP, MYSQL, WORDPRESS, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, and JQUERY.

Web Developer at Web Media World Karachi (January 2010 - January 2011)

WEB Developer worked on

PHP, MYSQL, WORDPRESS, JOOMLA, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, JQUERY.

Projects

Property Match Real State September 2017

MatchPropertyDirect matches sellers and buyers for a property direct sale. Sellers will input the details of their home for a fee and have direct contact with potential buyers to negotiate a sale. It will remove the role of a middle men and their commission. It will allow the purchasers to have an intimate understanding of the home and its location.

Technologies used in this portal are

Laravel PHP, MYSQL HTML, CSS **JAVASCRIPT** JQUERY, UNITY WEB SERVICES

http://107.6.184.93/MatchPropertyDirect/

Maverick Game

September 2015 to December 2015

The Online Gaming portal. This application provides online games to play to get rewards. These games are playing with coins i.e. one coin for one game. User who register will get 5 free coins And can play five games and score which he/she makes in games will save and display on leaderboard User will get points against his/her score and there is point's leader board also where users total points will display with his/her rank

There is rewards in this portal which can be redeem/get by game score points Technologies used in this portal are

PHP, MYSQL HTML, CSS JAVASCRIPT JQUERY, UNITY WEB SERVICES

https://www.maverickgame.com/

The Fun Kids June 2015 to August 2015

The Online Website for Kids. The online games, puzzles activities, rhymes and stories will help in educating your kid with basic knowledge and instilling imagination and creativity. The Fun Kids is going to boost your kid's memory by improving his cognitive learning abilities and developing a creative mindset, making them think out-of-the-box. Our mom forum is an interactive engaging blog to help mommies discuss their parental issues and their baby affairs. We hope your journey with us will be refreshing and full of fun.

Technologies: PHP, MYSQL HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, FLASH, UNITY, WEB SERVICES

Love That Fit

March 2013 to May 2015

The Online application for providing best clothes to customers. Customer can register, log in and provide the details of his/her clothes measurement so that they can select the best fit clothes.

Application has different types of user accounts like Retailer, Family accounts, and Store owners.

All the user can register, log in and try the available Product by specifying their measurement.

Technologies: PHP, MYSQL HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, FLASH, UNITY, WEB SERVICES

http://dev.lovethatfit.com

Conference Projects

September 2012 to September 2012

This project contains the speakers list and their conferences at any cermony and also ticketing system for registered users.

Technologies: PHP, MYSQL HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, FLASH, UNITY, WEB SERVICES

Dr Smita Sinha's

September 2012 to October 2012

Gynecologist web application of malaysia Dr Smita Sinha's with patient appointment online system

Technologies: PHP, MYSQL HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, FLASH, UNITY, WEB SERVICES

Health Care Jobs

July 2012 to July 2012

http://okjobmalaysia.com/

My Portfolio Site

http://107.6.184.93/MatchPropertyDirect/

http://brandscapes.com.pk/

http://www·maverickgame·com/

http://dev·lovethatfit·com

https://www.owbaz.com/

http://www.thefunkids.com/

http://sanfordairport.dev.revps.com/

http://www.thefunkids.com/

http://www.olams.com/

http://ebooklicense.com/

http://okjobmalaysia.com/

http://dlfaculty.com/

http://midwestvagroup.com/

http://www.pickhealthcarejobs.com/

http://coryjohnson.ca/

Education

University of Sindh

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 2005 - 2009